FUYUAN LYU

fuyuan.lyu@mail.mcgill.com 845 Sherbrooke St W, Montreal, Quebec fuyuanlyu.github.io

SUMMARY

I'm currently a Ph.D. candidate at McGill University. I am fortunate to be advised by Prof Jin Guo and Prof Xue Liu.

Prior to joining McGill, I got my bachelor's degree of Computer Science and Zhiyuan Honour Degree of Engineering from Shanghai Jiao Tong University(SJTU). I was advised by Prof Li Jiang and Prof Xiaokang Yang.

My research interest lies in utilizing Recommendation System and Graph Neural Network in the Software Engineering domain.

EDUCATION

- PhD, Computer Science, McGill University, 2019-2024(exp.)
- BEng, Computer Science, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2015-2019
- Zhiyuan Honor Degree for BEng, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2015-2019

PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINT

Fuyuan Lyu*, Xing Tang*, Huifeng Guo, Ruiming Tang, Xiuqiang He, Rui Zhang, Xue Liu, "Memorize, Factorize, or be Naïve: Learning Optimal Feature Interaction Methods for CTR Prediction", In Proceedings of the 38th IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE) 2022

Yuecai Zhu, Fuyuan Lyu, Chengming Hu, Xi Chen, Xue Liu, "Encoder-Decoder Architecture for Supervised Dynamic Graph Learning: A Survey", arXiv preprint, 2022

Tian Li, Jieru Zhao, Chaoqun Chu, Fuyuan Lyu, Xiaoqiao Xu, Mengqi Cao, Beilei Sun, Zhezhi He, Minyi Guo, Li Jiang, "Dualflow Training Framework to Exploit Structured Sparsity", In Work-In-Progress sessions at the 2021 Design Automation Conference(DAC)

Fuyuan Lyu, Shien Zhu, and Weichen Liu. "Cross-filter compression for CNN inference acceleration." arXiv preprint 2020.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Huawei Noah's Ark Lab, Canada

August 2021 to Present

Research Intern

Advisor: Dr. Yingxue Zhang • Optimal Embedding Table for CTR Prediction: Study the influence of the size of embedding table in CTR Prediction.

Propose a unified framework to optimize the size of the embedding table as well as model parameters automatically.

Huawei Noah's Ark Lab March 2021 to August 2021

Research Intern

Advisor: Dr. Xing Tang

 Optimal Modelling Methods for Feature Interaction in CTR Prediction: Study the influence of modelling methods for feature interaction. Propose a novel deep CTR prediction framework including various modelling methods and a two-stage learning algorithm to select the optimal for each feature interaction automatically.

McGill University Sept 2019 to present

Research Assistant

Advisor: Prof. Jin Guo & Prof. Xue Liu

- Hardware Adaptive Pruning: Studied the pruning problem in the resource-contrained secanrios. Propose a Hardware Adaptive Pruning method that effectively prunes the models considering hardware constraints as part of the loss function. Adopt model transferability as an additional evaluation metric for pruning methods to reflect practical concerns when deploying.
- Recommending Repositories to Support Reproducibility: Studied the reproducibility of different ML papers. Utilized Recommendator System on GitHub to support reproducing ML papers.

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Feb 2019 to Aug 2019

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Li Jiang

• Dual-flow Training Framework to Exploit Structured Sparsity: Support structured sparsity from framework level. Propose a flexible dual-flow mechanism to decouple the non-zero data and the sparse network structure. Integrate the dual-flow mechanism into the deep learning compiler stack built on TVM.

Nanyang Technological University

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Weichen Liu

• Cross-filter Compression: Address the conflict between uniform quantization and compact network design when speedup CNN. Explored CNN spatial-adjunct layer property and proposed cross-filter compression method.

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Jun 2017 to Feb 2018

Aug 2018 to Feb 2019

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Xiaokang Yang

- Explored the possibility of more realistic cloth transfer by generating and transferring structure in 3D dimension.
- Designed a specific generative adversarial network to animate cartoon figures.

TEACHING AND MENTORING EXPERIENCE

- 2020 Winter COMP303 Teaching Assistant
- Reviewer of Transaction on Service Computing

SELECTED AWARDS

- Wolfe Fellowship in Sci & Tech, 2019-2022
- Grad Excellence Award of McGill University, 2019-2022
- Zhiyuan Honor Degree of Engineering of Shanghai Jiao Tong University(1%), 2019
- Zhiyuan Oversea Research Scholarship (1st class) of Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2019
- Zhiyuan Outstanding Student Scholarship of Shanghai Jiao Tong University(5%), 2019
- Microsoft Intelligence Award, awarded to 4/438 participants in the 1st HACKxFDU Hackathon, 2016.

SKILLS

Software Python, C++, Java

Languages English: professional proficiency. Mandarin: native.